

TIERNAN CUTLER

UX/UI DESIGNER & DESIGN DIRECTOR

+39 331 948 9317

tiernancutler@gmail.com www.tiernancutler.com

After interning as a graphic designer at Sotheby's, I moved to Florence, Italy to pursue my MA in Graphic Design, and I started working with a start-up tour operator there. Over the past 9 years with them, I've stepped into a variety of roles in order to support the company's growing needs ranging from tour guide to graphic designer to sales manager. I've since risen through ranks and am now Director of both the Sales and Design departments. When tourism came to a halt, to meet the moment in an everchanging world and industry, I expanded my skill set to focus on user-centered design by completing year-long UX/UI certification course.

EXPERIENCE

2016-Present

DESIGN DIRECTOR Bus2alps

2019-2021 **SALES DIRECTOR**Bus2alps

2009-Present
FREELANCE GRAPHIC,
UX/UI DESIGNER &
BRAND CONSULTANT

Created brand identity, oversee execution of all brand content, and manage design teams.

- Responsible for: triannual 80 page brochures, exposition display material, social media content and website.
- Overhauled website structure for better user experience and more efficient booking process.
- Rebranded the CI and implemented across all platforms.
- Instrumental in launching new products and creation of cross-platform promotional materials.
- Communicate effectively with overseas offices and vendors to ensure product execution.

Promoted from Senior Designer (2014-2016) and Graphic Designer (2012-2014).

Manage sales teams located in Florence, Rome, Prague and Barcelona (35 sellers).

- Develop and implement sales strategies for campaigns.
- Analyze weekly BI reporting to drive and grow pipelines.
- Collaborate with the operations department to ensure. tours operate with a positive profit margin.
- Increased annual earnings by 38%.
- Increased staff retention by 16%.

Promoted from Florence Sales Manager (2017-2018), Sales Specialist and Head Tour guide (2012-2017).

Contracted by various clients for a range of cross-platform requests. Examples include:

- Developed concept, graphic design layout and copy for "College Survival Guide" adopted by Clorox equity business as their online back-to-school campaign.
- Rebranded CI and redesigned the UX/UI of the website for Lotus Retreats.
- Home Sweet Home brand creation and social media content consultant.

EDUCATION

UX/UI DESIGN CERTIFICATION

CareerFoundry Apr 2020 - Apr 2021

M.A. GRAPHIC DESIGN

Florence Institute of Design International Aug 2011 - May 2012

B.A. ART HISTORY

Bowdoin College Aug 2007 - May 2011

GRAPHIC DESIGN CERTIFICATE COURSE

Maine College of Art Summers 2009 & 2011

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Native

ITALIAN

C1 Level

SKILLS, PROGRAMS & TOOLS

UX/UI

UX research: Competitor
Analysis, User Surveys &
Interviews, Data Analysis
Affinity mapping
User personas
User journeys and flows
Wireframes and prototyping
User testing
Style guide creation
Frontend development

GRAPHIC DESIGN

Layout composition
Typography
Brochures and other
print design
Website design
Social media design:
Facebook, Instagram,
Pinterest, Ads
Company branding
Package design

PROGRAMS & TOOLS

Abobe Suite: InDesign,
Photoshop, Illustrator,
Lightroom and XD
Figma
Sketch
Marvel
Microsoft Office
Atom
CSS and HTML
Javascript